<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[The New Dark Times]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[All the news that's fit to print, minus the sad stuff]]></description>
        <link>https://thegoodnews.tiiny.site</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2025 14:52:04 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://thegoodnews.tiiny.site/goodnews.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2025 14:31:39 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>60</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Czech Dam Project Was Stalled by Bureaucracy. Beavers Built Their Own.]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[The dam project, drafted in 2018 and based on a former military training site south of Prague, had been delayed by land negotiations. Local beavers built several dams, saving the government more than one million euros.]]></description>
            <link>https://archive.is/2025/https://www.nytimes.com/2025/02/12/world/europe/beavers-prague-czech-republic-dam.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.nytimes.com/2025/02/12/world/europe/beavers-prague-czech-republic-dam.html</guid>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[New York Times]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2025 14:31:39 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Hamas Signals Progress Toward Resumed Hostage Releases]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[The group said that mediators were working “to remove obstacles and close gaps” after the cease-fire deal with Israel hit a roadblock.]]></description>
            <link>https://archive.is/2025/https://www.nytimes.com/2025/02/13/world/middleeast/gaza-israel-ceasefire-hostages.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.nytimes.com/2025/02/13/world/middleeast/gaza-israel-ceasefire-hostages.html</guid>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[New York Times]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2025 13:03:06 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[‘I want more joy, less killing’: Jamaicans say police alone cannot quell gang crime]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Experts, and children in violence-torn areas, see factors such as education and land ownership as keys to progress</p><p>The <a href="http://www.operation-restoration.org/">Operation Restoration Christian</a> school sits amid a line of patched-up housing blocks and streetside cookshops in Trench Town. In an area known as one of Kingston’s inner-city crime hotspots, it was founded as a haven for children caught up in gang violence.</p><p>Inside, boys in smart khaki uniforms and girls in yellow shirts and pleated burgundy skirts sit chatting in groups. The classrooms are adorned with images of Jamaican heroes, such as Marcus Garvey and past prime ministers – a reminder to the children, says the principal, Robert Dixon, of what they might one day accomplish.</p> <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2025/feb/13/jamaica-gang-crime-police">Continue reading...</a>]]></description>
            <link>https://archive.is/2025/https://www.theguardian.com/world/2025/feb/13/jamaica-gang-crime-police</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.theguardian.com/world/2025/feb/13/jamaica-gang-crime-police</guid>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[Guardian US]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2025 11:00:04 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[US wildfire suppressants rife with toxic heavy metals, study finds]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Suppressants a ‘major’ source of toxic pollution that causes heavy-metal levels to spike in the environment</p><p>The US federal government and chemical makers have long concealed the contents of pink wildfire suppressants widely spread by firefighting aircraft to contain blazes, but new test results provide alarming answers – the substances are rife with cadmium, arsenic, chromium and other toxic heavy metals.</p><p>The suppressants are a “major” source of toxic pollution that causes heavy-metal levels to spike in the environment, and the products themselves contain metal levels up to 3,000 times above drinking water limits, the <a href="https://pubs.acs.org/doi/epdf/10.1021/acs.estlett.4c00727?ref=article_openPDF">peer-reviewed research</a> found.</p> <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/feb/13/us-wildfire-suppressants-toxic-study">Continue reading...</a>]]></description>
            <link>https://archive.is/2025/https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/feb/13/us-wildfire-suppressants-toxic-study</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/feb/13/us-wildfire-suppressants-toxic-study</guid>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[Guardian US]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2025 11:00:02 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Liberal Vets Group Gives Spanberger Boost in Virginia Governor’s Race]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[The $500,000 donation to the campaign of Abigail Spanberger, a former representative and C.I.A. officer, is the largest direct contribution in VoteVets’ 20-year history.]]></description>
            <link>https://archive.is/2025/https://www.nytimes.com/2025/02/13/us/politics/spanberger-votevets-virginia-governor.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.nytimes.com/2025/02/13/us/politics/spanberger-votevets-virginia-governor.html</guid>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[New York Times]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2025 10:04:34 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[‘No to ethnic cleansing’: over 350 rabbis sign US ad assailing Trump’s Gaza plan]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Jewish creatives and activists also sign New York Times ad after US president’s proposal to ‘take over Gaza’</p><p>More than 350 rabbis, alongside additional signatories including Jewish creatives and activists, have signed an ad in the New York Times in which they condemn <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2025/feb/05/donald-trump-plan-to-take-over-gaza-strip-netanyahu-visit">Donald Trump’s proposal</a> for the effective ethnic cleansing of Palestinians from Gaza.</p><p>The ad, which was signed by rabbis including Sharon Brous, Roly Matalon and Alissa Wise, as well as Jewish creatives and activists including Tony Kushner, Ilana Glazer, Naomi Klein and Joaquin Phoenix, says: “Trump has called for the removal of all Palestinians from Gaza. Jewish people say no to ethnic cleansing!”</p> <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/feb/13/rabbis-ad-trump-gaza-plan">Continue reading...</a>]]></description>
            <link>https://archive.is/2025/https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/feb/13/rabbis-ad-trump-gaza-plan</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/feb/13/rabbis-ad-trump-gaza-plan</guid>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[Guardian US]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2025 10:00:04 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[ProPublica Updates Supreme Connections Database With Previously Missing Disclosures]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[
                <p class="byline">
                by <a class="name" href="https://www.propublica.org/people/sergio-hernandez">Sergio Hernández</a>                </p>
                                             

                                                                    
            
                <p>ProPublica is a nonprofit newsroom that investigates abuses of power. Sign up to receive <a href="https://www.propublica.org/newsletters/the-big-story?source=54G&amp;placement=top-note&amp;region=national">our biggest stories</a> as soon as they’re published.</p>

            

                

      
  



                    
<p data-pp-blocktype="copy" data-pp-id="1.0">We updated our <a href="https://projects.propublica.org/supreme-connections/">Supreme Connections database</a> with new disclosures on Thursday, adding Justice Samuel Alito’s deferred 2023 filing and eight previously missing disclosures from Justice Clarence Thomas dating back to the 1990s.</p>

<p data-pp-blocktype="copy" data-pp-id="1.1">Supreme Connections is our database that makes it easy for anyone to browse justices’ financial disclosures and to search for connections to people and companies mentioned within them.</p>
        
    
                    
<p data-pp-blocktype="copy" data-pp-id="3.0">This update includes Alito’s 2023 disclosure, which was released in August after he received an extension, as well as eight Thomas filings from the 1990s provided by <a href="http://documented.net/">Documented</a>. Those filings were not previously available in our database. While federal ethics law requires judges to file these disclosures each year, the law requires most filings to be destroyed after six years, making many past disclosures hard to find.</p>

<p data-pp-blocktype="copy" data-pp-id="3.1">Alito’s disclosure includes $900 in concert tickets from Princess Gloria von Thurn und Taxis, which The New York Times reported were <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/10/22/us/politics/samuel-alito-princess-gloria.html">for her annual music festival</a> in Regensburg, Germany. The Bavarian aristocrat <a href="https://www.vanityfair.com/news/2006/06/princesstnt200606">once dubbed the “punk princess”</a> has reinvented herself in recent decades, closely aligning with European conservative and Catholic circles.</p>

<p data-pp-blocktype="copy" data-pp-id="3.2">The newly added Thomas filings, which cover 1992 to 1999, reveal more than 100 gifts or travel-related reimbursements, including more than a dozen private flights, cigars from the late conservative commentator Rush Limbaugh, and a 1997 trip paid for by billionaire Harlan Crow to Bohemian Grove, an all-male retreat in northern California. ProPublica previously reported how <a href="https://www.propublica.org/series/supreme-court-scotus">Crow has provided Thomas with extensive undisclosed luxury travel</a>, including several other trips to Bohemian Grove. Thomas has argued he did not need to disclose such gifts.</p>

<p data-pp-blocktype="copy" data-pp-id="3.3"><a href="https://projects.propublica.org/supreme-connections/">Browse the database</a> to learn more.</p>
        
    
                            
             

                                    
        
                        <p>Do you have any tips on the Supreme Court? Josh Kaplan can be reached by email at <a href="mailto:joshua.kaplan@propublica.org">joshua.kaplan@propublica.org</a> and by Signal or WhatsApp at 734-834-9383. Justin Elliott can be reached by email at <a href="mailto:justin@propublica.org">justin@propublica.org</a> or by Signal or WhatsApp at 774-826-6240.</p>

        

    
                                         ]]></description>
            <link>https://archive.is/2025/https://www.propublica.org/article/propublica-supreme-connections-database-new-filings</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.propublica.org/article/propublica-supreme-connections-database-new-filings</guid>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[ProPublica]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2025 10:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[‘Here lives the monster’s brain’: the man who exposed Switzerland’s dirty secrets]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Inspired by Che Guevara, Jean Ziegler has spent the past 60 years exposing how Switzerland enabled global wrongdoing. His enemies accuse him of treason</p><p>In early 1964, Jean Ziegler, a young Swiss politician, received a phone call from a man claiming to represent Ernesto “Che” Guevara, the Cuban revolutionary and minister of industry. Che would be in Geneva in March for a UN conference on trade policy, and some comrades had suggested Jean might be his chauffeur during his stay. Was Ziegler available for the gig?</p><p>Today, in his tenth decade of life, Ziegler is Switzerland’s most notorious public intellectual. That’s because, over the course of writing about 30 books, serving for close to three decades in the Swiss parliament, and relentlessly crusading for leftwing causes in his free time, Ziegler has made a career of unsparing criticism of his home country and its outsize influence on the rest of the world. In the 1960s, though, he was just another eager young leftist, waiting for his chance to change the world.</p> <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/news/2025/feb/13/here-lives-the-monsters-brain-the-man-who-exposed-switzerlands-dirty-secrets">Continue reading...</a>]]></description>
            <link>https://archive.is/2025/https://www.theguardian.com/news/2025/feb/13/here-lives-the-monsters-brain-the-man-who-exposed-switzerlands-dirty-secrets</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.theguardian.com/news/2025/feb/13/here-lives-the-monsters-brain-the-man-who-exposed-switzerlands-dirty-secrets</guid>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[Guardian US]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2025 05:00:47 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ex-officer convicted in fatal shooting of Black man at New Mexico gas station]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Prosecutors said Brad Lunsford, found guilty of voluntary manslaughter, shot Presley Eze at point-blank range in 2022</p><p>A former police officer was found guilty on Wednesday of voluntary manslaughter in the killing of Presley Eze during a 2022 confrontation at a New Mexico gas station.</p><p>Brad Lunsford, who is white, had pleaded not guilty in the fatal shooting of Eze, who was Black. The former Las Cruces officer’s attorney, Jose Coronado, said he would ask the judge to review the verdict for its legal sufficiency.</p> <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/feb/12/new-mexico-police-shooting-gas-station">Continue reading...</a>]]></description>
            <link>https://archive.is/2025/https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/feb/12/new-mexico-police-shooting-gas-station</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/feb/12/new-mexico-police-shooting-gas-station</guid>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[Guardian US]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2025 02:14:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Czech Dam Project Was Stalled by Bureaucracy. Beavers Built Their Own.]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[The dam project, drafted in 2018 and based on a former military training site south of Prague, had been delayed by land negotiations. Local beavers built several dams, saving the government more than one million euros.]]></description>
            <link>https://archive.is/2025/https://www.nytimes.com/2025/02/12/world/europe/czech-dam-project-was-stalled-by-bureaucracy-beavers-built-their-own.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.nytimes.com/2025/02/12/world/europe/czech-dam-project-was-stalled-by-bureaucracy-beavers-built-their-own.html</guid>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[New York Times]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2025 00:45:31 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Austrian Coalition Talks Collapse, Averting, for Now, a Far-Right Chancellor]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[The plan by the far-right Freedom Party to run Austria was halted by a disagreement over who would lead the all-important Interior Ministry.]]></description>
            <link>https://archive.is/2025/https://www.nytimes.com/2025/02/12/world/europe/austria-coalition-talks-far-right-chancellor.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.nytimes.com/2025/02/12/world/europe/austria-coalition-talks-far-right-chancellor.html</guid>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[New York Times]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2025 00:43:01 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Maria Teresa Horta, the Last of Portugal’s ‘Three Marias,’ Dies at 87]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[The book on which she collaborated with two fellow feminists drew global attention to the repression of women under their country’s dictatorship.]]></description>
            <link>https://archive.is/2025/https://www.nytimes.com/2025/02/11/world/europe/maria-teresa-horta-dead.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.nytimes.com/2025/02/11/world/europe/maria-teresa-horta-dead.html</guid>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[New York Times]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2025 22:16:20 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[California’s Scary Product Warning Labels Might Be Working, Study Says]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[Products must state if they contain chemicals tied to cancer or other risks. As a result, manufacturers have pulled back from using the chemicals, researchers found.]]></description>
            <link>https://archive.is/2025/https://www.nytimes.com/2025/02/12/climate/california-chemical-warning-labels.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.nytimes.com/2025/02/12/climate/california-chemical-warning-labels.html</guid>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[New York Times]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2025 22:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Lawsuit Seeks Access to Migrants Held at Guantanamo Bay]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[Advocacy groups say the Trump administration is denying detainees their legal rights.]]></description>
            <link>https://archive.is/2025/https://www.wsj.com/us-news/law/lawsuit-seeks-access-to-migrants-held-at-guantanamo-bay-2d6ad874</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.wsj.com/us-news/law/lawsuit-seeks-access-to-migrants-held-at-guantanamo-bay-2d6ad874</guid>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[Wall Street Journal]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2025 21:56:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pentagon Official: Hegseth’s Campaign to Scrub DEI History Is a “Dumb” Distraction]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Defense Secretary Pete Hegseth is trying to eliminate all Defense Department DEI efforts. It hasn’t been entirely successful.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://theintercept.com/2025/02/12/pete-hegseth-military-trump-diversity/">Pentagon Official: Hegseth’s Campaign to Scrub DEI History Is a “Dumb” Distraction</a> appeared first on <a href="https://theintercept.com">The Intercept</a>.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://archive.is/2025/https://theintercept.com/2025/02/12/pete-hegseth-military-trump-diversity/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://theintercept.com/2025/02/12/pete-hegseth-military-trump-diversity/</guid>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[The Intercept]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2025 21:18:57 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Belarus frees three detainees including US citizen and journalist]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Journalist with US-funded broadcaster among those in release hailed by ambassador as ‘big day for team America’</p><p><a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/belarus">Belarus</a> has released three detainees including a veteran journalist for a US government-funded broadcaster and a US citizen, the White House said on Wednesday.</p><p>The White House press secretary, Karoline Leavitt, confirmed the release on Wednesday of three people including “one American and two individuals from Belarus, one of whom worked for Radio Liberty”. The released American has not been identified.</p> <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2025/feb/12/belarus-prisoner-release-andrey-kuznechyk">Continue reading...</a>]]></description>
            <link>https://archive.is/2025/https://www.theguardian.com/world/2025/feb/12/belarus-prisoner-release-andrey-kuznechyk</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.theguardian.com/world/2025/feb/12/belarus-prisoner-release-andrey-kuznechyk</guid>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[Guardian US]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2025 21:01:40 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Belarus Frees an American and 2 Others as It Tries to Thaw Relations]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[Aleksandr G. Lukashenko, Belarus’s autocratic president and Russia’s closest ally, has taken steps to soften his country’s isolation from the West.]]></description>
            <link>https://archive.is/2025/https://www.nytimes.com/2025/02/12/world/europe/belarus-prisoner-release.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.nytimes.com/2025/02/12/world/europe/belarus-prisoner-release.html</guid>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[New York Times]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2025 20:32:25 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Malcolm X’s visit to West Midlands to be remembered in mural]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Street art will mark 60 years since US civil rights leader’s trip to Smethwick shortly before his assassination</p><p>It was a moment that united the US civil rights movement with the anti-racist movement in Britain, helping to change the country – and to mark its 60th anniversary it will be commemorated with a mural.</p><p>On 12 February 1965, the black American activist Malcolm X visited Smethwick, in the West Midlands after what is remembered as <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2014/oct/15/britains-most-racist-election-smethwick-50-years-on">the most racist election campaign the UK has ever seen</a>.</p> <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/feb/12/malcolm-x-visit-smethwick-midlands-60th-anniversary-mural">Continue reading...</a>]]></description>
            <link>https://archive.is/2025/https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/feb/12/malcolm-x-visit-smethwick-midlands-60th-anniversary-mural</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/feb/12/malcolm-x-visit-smethwick-midlands-60th-anniversary-mural</guid>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[Guardian US]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2025 18:53:14 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[New inflation numbers are at odds with Donald Trump’s promise to lower prices]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>The president repeatedly claimed he would lower prices during the election campaign, but that’s not an easy task</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.theguardian.com/business/2025/feb/12/trump-january-inflation">Inflation gains speed despite Trump vow to ‘rapidly’ cut prices</a></li></ul><p>As tens of millions of Americans prepared to watch the Super Bowl this weekend, <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/donaldtrump">Donald Trump</a> sat for the customary pre-game presidential interview.</p><p>Trump was elected after pledging to bring down prices fast as much of the country grappled with the cost of living after years of heightened inflation. So when the Fox News anchor asked would families start to feel the impact, the president changed the subject.</p> <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/business/2025/feb/12/prices-higher-trump-inflation">Continue reading...</a>]]></description>
            <link>https://archive.is/2025/https://www.theguardian.com/business/2025/feb/12/prices-higher-trump-inflation</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.theguardian.com/business/2025/feb/12/prices-higher-trump-inflation</guid>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[Guardian US]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2025 16:26:39 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Eight inspectors general sue to challenge firings by Trump – live]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>President dismissed 18 officials within days of taking office, which appears to contradict federal law that requires Congress to have 30 days notice</p><p>Several <strong>Democratic</strong> state attorneys general warned that the country was in the grip of a full-blown constitutional crisis, as they battle <strong><a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/donaldtrump">Donald Trump</a></strong> in court over actions they argue are lawless and in some cases brazenly unconstitutional.</p><p>“We are on the brink of a dictatorship, and America has never been in a more dangerous position than she is today,” Kris Mayes, the attorney general of Arizona, said at a press conference in <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/los-angeles">Los Angeles</a> on Tuesday.</p> <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/live/2025/feb/12/trump-musk-modi-tariffs-usaid-us-politics-live-news">Continue reading...</a>]]></description>
            <link>https://archive.is/2025/https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/live/2025/feb/12/trump-musk-modi-tariffs-usaid-us-politics-live-news</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/live/2025/feb/12/trump-musk-modi-tariffs-usaid-us-politics-live-news</guid>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[Guardian US]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2025 16:13:42 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>