<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[The New Dark Times - good]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[All the news that's fit to print, minus the sad stuff]]></description>
        <link>https://lovemedicine.github.io/goodnews</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2025 19:33:58 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://lovemedicine.github.io/goodnews/good.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2025 19:20:00 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>60</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[U.S. Claims Immigrants Held at Guantanamo Are “Worst of the Worst.” Their Families Say They’re Being Unfairly Targeted.]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[
                <p class="byline">
                by <a class="name" href="https://www.propublica.org/people/perla-trevizo">Perla Trevizo</a> and <span class="name">Mica Rosenberg</span>, <a href="https://www.propublica.org/texas">ProPublica and The Texas Tribune</a>                </p>
                                             

        
                        <p>ProPublica is a nonprofit newsroom that investigates abuses of power. Sign up to receive <a href="https://www.propublica.org/newsletters/the-big-story?source=www.propublica.org&amp;placement=top-note&amp;region=texas">our biggest stories</a> as soon as they’re published.</p>
<p>This article is co-published with The Texas Tribune, a nonprofit, nonpartisan local newsroom that informs and engages with Texans. Sign up for <a href="https://www.texastribune.org/newsletters/briefweekly/">The Brief Weekly</a> to get up to speed on their essential coverage of Texas issues.</p>

        

    
      
  



                    
<p data-pp-blocktype="copy" data-pp-id="1.0">The military planes departed from Texas in quick succession, eight flights in as many days. Each one carried more than a dozen immigrants that the U.S. alleged are the “worst of the worst” kinds of criminals, including members of a violent Venezuelan street gang.</p>

<p data-pp-blocktype="copy" data-pp-id="1.1">Since Feb. 4, the Trump administration has flown about 100 immigrant detainees to the U.S. naval base in Guantanamo Bay, Cuba, a facility better known for having held those suspected of plotting the 9/11 terrorist attacks. Officials have widely touted the flights as a demonstration of President Donald Trump’s commitment to one of the central promises of his campaign, and they’ve distributed photos of some of the immigrants at both takeoff and landing. But they have not released the names of those they’re holding or provided details about their alleged crimes.</p>

<p data-pp-blocktype="copy" data-pp-id="1.2">In recent days, however, information about the flights and the people on them has emerged that calls the government’s narrative into question. ProPublica and The Texas Tribune have identified nearly a dozen Venezuelan immigrants who have been transferred to Guantanamo. The <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2025/02/12/us/gitmo-migrants-trump.html?smid=nytcore-ios-share&amp;amp;referringSource=articleShare">New York Times</a> published a larger list with some, but not all, of the same names.</p>

<p data-pp-blocktype="copy" data-pp-id="1.3">For three of the Guantanamo detainees who had been held at an immigration detention center in El Paso, Texas, ProPublica and the Tribune obtained records about their criminal histories and spoke to their families. The three men are all Venezuelan. Each had been detained by immigration authorities soon after crossing the U.S.-Mexico border and was being held in custody, awaiting deportation. In some cases, they had been languishing for months because Venezuela, until recently, was largely not accepting deportees. According to U.S. federal court records, two of them had no crimes on their records except for illegal entry. The third had picked up an additional charge while in detention, for kicking an officer while being restrained during a riot.</p>

<p data-pp-blocktype="copy" data-pp-id="1.4">Relatives of the three men said in interviews on Tuesday that they have been left entirely in the dark about their loved ones. They all said that their relatives were not criminals, and two provided records from the Venezuelan Interior Ministry and other documents to support their statements. They said the U.S. government has given them neither information about the detainees’ whereabouts nor the ability to speak with them.</p>

<p data-pp-blocktype="copy" data-pp-id="1.5">Attorneys say they have also been denied access. The <a href="https://www.aclu.org/documents/gitmo-lawsuit-filing">American Civil Liberties Union filed a lawsuit</a> on Wednesday, arguing that the U.S. Constitution gives the detainees rights to legal representation that shouldn’t be stripped away just because they have been moved to Guantanamo.</p>

<p data-pp-blocktype="copy" data-pp-id="1.6">“Never before have people been taken from U.S. soil and sent to Guantanamo, and then denied access to lawyers and the outside world,” said Lee Gelernt, the lead attorney in the ACLU case. “It is difficult to think of anything so flagrantly at odds with the fundamental principles on which our country was built.”</p>
        
    
                    
<p data-pp-blocktype="copy" data-pp-id="4.0">Yesika Palma sobbed as she spoke about her brother Jose Daniel Simancas, a 30-year-old construction worker, and how it felt to think of him being treated like a terrorist when all he’d done was attempt to come to the United States in pursuit of a decent job. Angela Sequera was distraught about not being able to speak to her son, Yoiker Sequera, who’d worked as a barber in Venezuela.</p>

<p data-pp-blocktype="copy" data-pp-id="4.1">Michel Duran expressed the same dismay about his son, Mayfreed Duran, who also worked as a barber. “To me it’s the desperation, the frustration that I know nothing of him,” he said in a phone interview in Spanish from his home in Venezuela. “It’s a terrible anguish. I don’t sleep.”</p>

<p data-pp-blocktype="copy" data-pp-id="4.2">In response to questions about the Guantanamo detentions, officials at the Department of Homeland Security insisted, without pointing to any evidence, that some — but not all — of the immigrants they have transferred to Guantanamo are violent gang members and others are “high-threat” criminals. “All these individuals committed a crime by entering the United States illegally,” an agency official said in a statement. Some detainees are being held in Guantanamo’s maximum-security prison while others are in the Migrant Operations Center that in the past has been used to house those intercepted at sea.</p>

<p data-pp-blocktype="copy" data-pp-id="4.3">DHS spokesperson Tricia McLaughlin, responding to the ACLU lawsuit, said in an email that there was a phone system that detainees could use to reach attorneys. Writing in all caps for emphasis, she added, “If the AMERICAN Civil Liberties Union cares more about highly dangerous criminal aliens including murders &amp; vicious gang members than they do about American citizens — they should change their name.”</p>

<p data-pp-blocktype="copy" data-pp-id="4.4">In the past, the <a href="https://www.propublica.org/article/family-separations-biden-russian-immigrants">U.S. government has withheld information about cases that it says involve a threat to national security</a>. In those cases, the authorities say, information they’re using to make custody determinations is confidential. The government said some of the people sent to Guantanamo are tied to the Tren de Aragua criminal organization, which Trump designated a <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/presidential-actions/2025/01/designating-cartels-and-other-organizations-as-foreign-terrorist-organizations-and-specially-designated-global-terrorists/">terrorist group</a> when he took office. Among the things law enforcement has used to identify members of the group have been certain tattoos, including stars, roses and crowns, though there’s disagreement on whether the practice is reliable. Lawyers have expressed concern that the government sometimes uses national security concerns as a pretext to avoid scrutiny.</p>

<p data-pp-blocktype="copy" data-pp-id="4.5">The Guantanamo detentions may be among the highest-profile moves the Trump administration has made as part of its mass deportation campaign, but federal agents have also fanned out across the country over the last several weeks to conduct raids in neighborhoods and workplaces. Data obtained by ProPublica and the Tribune shows that from Jan. 20 through the first days of February, there have been at least 14,000 immigration arrests. Around 44% of them were of people with criminal convictions, and of those, close to half were convicted of misdemeanors. Still, Trump’s border czar, Tom Homan, has said that he’s not satisfied with the pace of enforcement.</p>

<p data-pp-blocktype="copy" data-pp-id="4.6">Government data obtained by the news organizations shows that the Trump administration has averaged about 500 deportations per day, well short of the more than 2,100 per day during the 2024 fiscal year under former President Joe Biden. However, the difference could be attributed to lower numbers of border crossings, which have been dropping since last year.</p>

<p data-pp-blocktype="copy" data-pp-id="4.7">Trump <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/presidential-actions/2025/01/expanding-migrant-operations-center-at-naval-station-guantanamo-bay-to-full-capacity/">directed the departments</a> of Defense and Homeland Security last month to prepare 30,000 beds at Guantanamo and later said the site was for “criminal illegal aliens threatening the American people.”</p>
        
    
                    

    
        

                        
                    
                

            Mayfreed Duran, left, Yoiker Sequera, center, and Jose Daniel Simancas are among the roughly 100 people the U.S. government has flown to a detention facility in Guantanamo Bay.
    
            (Edited by ProPublica, source images courtesy of Duran’s, Sequera’s and Simancas’ families)
    
    
    

    

        
    
                    
<p data-pp-blocktype="copy" data-pp-id="6.0">Relatives of three of those currently detained in Guantanamo said the immigrants all had tattoos. And one of them, Simancas, was from Aragua, the state <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/americas/what-is-venezuelan-prison-gang-tren-de-aragua-2024-07-11/">where Tren de Aragua was born</a>. The detainees’ relatives dispute that their loved ones have anything to do with the group. “This doesn’t make sense. He’s a family man,” Palma said in Spanish of her brother. “Having tattoos is not a sin.”</p>

<p data-pp-blocktype="copy" data-pp-id="6.1">Palma, who is currently living in Ecuador, said her brother left Venezuela years ago, first living for a time in Ecuador and then in Costa Rica. He decided to try his luck in the United States last year, crossing with a group that included his wife and cousin, who were soon released into the U.S. to pursue asylum claims, they both said in interviews. All three women said Simancas was proud of his work on construction sites and shared TikTok videos he made showing the progress of some of his projects, set to music. Simancas called his cousin on Feb. 7 saying he was being taken to Guantanamo. “It is truly distressing,” his sister said. “I have to have faith because if I break down I can’t help him.”</p>

<p data-pp-blocktype="copy" data-pp-id="6.2">Duran’s father only learned of his son’s potential whereabouts after recognizing his face in a TikTok video with some of the images released by the U.S. government of men in gray sweats and shackles being led into military planes in El Paso.</p>

<p data-pp-blocktype="copy" data-pp-id="6.3">Duran had left Venezuela hoping to one day open his own barbershop in Chicago, where he had relatives. He described his son, who has a toddler, as a jokester and a dedicated worker. Duran was detained in July 2023 on his third attempt crossing the border, his father said. He remained in detention following a conviction for assaulting a federal officer during a riot at the immigration center in El Paso in August, about a month after his arrival. He’d called his father on Feb. 6, asking him to gather documentation that could prove he had no criminal record in Venezuela because officials were trying to tie him to Tren de Aragua. That was the last his father heard of him.</p>

<p data-pp-blocktype="copy" data-pp-id="6.4">Angela Sequera was used to talking to her son every day on the phone while he was detained in El Paso, but then she abruptly stopped hearing from him. On Sunday she got a call from a detainee inside the El Paso center telling her that her son Yoiker had been transferred, but she wasn’t able to speak to him; when she looked him up online, it still showed him as being at the border.</p>

<p data-pp-blocktype="copy" data-pp-id="6.5">She’d last heard from him a day earlier. “Estoy cansado,” I’m exhausted, she said he told her in Spanish. “It’s unfair that I’m still detained.” He’d been held inside the detention center in El Paso since September, after turning himself in to the Border Patrol in Presidio, nearly four hours south of El Paso.</p>

<p data-pp-blocktype="copy" data-pp-id="6.6">Yoiker Sequera, who was first identified by the online publication <a href="https://migrantinsider.com/">Migrant Insider</a>, is among the three Venezuelans named in the lawsuit filed by the ACLU. The 25-year-old had wanted to be a barber ever since he was a boy, his mother said, just like his uncle. That’s how he made a living wherever he went, in Venezuela, Ecuador, Colombia. He continued to cut hair along the migrant route, as he was trying last year to make his way to his family in California, and inside the detention center.</p>

<p data-pp-blocktype="copy" data-pp-id="6.7">Angela Sequera said her son had planned on crossing the border and trying to seek asylum in the United States. “Now they want to tie him to criminal gangs. Everything that’s happening is so unfair.”</p>
        
             

                                    
        
                        <p>We are still reporting. Do you have information about the U.S. immigration system you want to share? You can reach <a href="https://www.propublica.org/tips/#signal">our tip line</a> on Signal at 917-512-0201. Please be as specific, detailed and clear as you can.</p>

        

    


                                    
        
                        <p><a href="https://www.propublica.org/people/pratheek-rebala">Pratheek Rebala</a> contributed reporting.</p>

        

    
                                         ]]></description>
            <link>https://archive.is/2025/https://www.propublica.org/article/trump-administration-migrants-guantanamo-bay</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.propublica.org/article/trump-administration-migrants-guantanamo-bay</guid>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[ProPublica]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2025 19:20:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Judge blocks Trump from firing head of US agency that investigates corruption]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Ruling reinstates Hampton Dellinger to office of special counsel as president targets bureaucrats with mass layoffs</p><p>A judge blocked <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/donaldtrump">Donald Trump</a>’s attempt to fire the head of a body that protects whistleblowers and investigates corruption.</p><p>Late on Wednesday Judge Amy Berman Jackson reversed the White House order sacking Hampton Dellinger as head of the Office of Special Counsel (OSC), and reinstated him in his post pending a court hearing set for 26 February.</p> <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/feb/13/trump-special-counsel-firings">Continue reading...</a>]]></description>
            <link>https://archive.is/2025/https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/feb/13/trump-special-counsel-firings</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/feb/13/trump-special-counsel-firings</guid>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[The Guardian]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2025 16:55:28 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[‘It’s a money game to them’: a son takes on UnitedHealth over his elderly father’s care]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Robby Martin has joined a lawsuit against UnitedHealth after the insurance giant cut off his father’s nursing home coverage – five days later his father died at home</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/feb/13/nursing-home-patients-insurance">Have you or a loved one experienced UHC coverage denials as a nursing home patient? Share you story.</a></li></ul><p>Two years ago, Robby Martin got an unsettling call from his father, Jackie. The 82-year-old told his son that a representative of the insurance giant UnitedHealth Group had barged into his nursing home room at 2.30 in the morning, announcing that he was going to be checked out at the end of the week.</p><p>Jackie Martin – who had been getting rehab at the nursing home after suffering a back fracture – still could not take more than a few steps without being out of breath.</p> <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/feb/13/unitedhealth-lawsuit-elderly-patients-care">Continue reading...</a>]]></description>
            <link>https://archive.is/2025/https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/feb/13/unitedhealth-lawsuit-elderly-patients-care</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/feb/13/unitedhealth-lawsuit-elderly-patients-care</guid>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[The Guardian]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2025 16:23:59 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Denver’s public school system sues Trump administration over Ice access to schools]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>School district says expanded immigration enforcement diverts resources and causes decreased attendance</p><p>The <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/denver">Denver</a> public school system (DPS) on Wednesday became the first US school district to sue the <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/trump-administration">Trump administration</a> over its policy of allowing Immigration and Customs Enforcement (Ice) agents in schools.</p><p><a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/colorado">Colorado</a>’s largest public school district argues in the federal lawsuit that the policy has forced schools to divert vital educational resources and caused attendance to plummet.</p> <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/feb/13/denver-trump-ice-lawsuit-schools">Continue reading...</a>]]></description>
            <link>https://archive.is/2025/https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/feb/13/denver-trump-ice-lawsuit-schools</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/feb/13/denver-trump-ice-lawsuit-schools</guid>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[The Guardian]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2025 15:34:31 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[US nursing home patients: have you or your loved one experienced coverage denials from UnitedHealthcare?]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>We would like to hear from people who have been denied access to care as a patient with the UnitedHealthcare Medicare advantage plan</p><p>An October 2024 <a href="https://www.hsgac.senate.gov/wp-content/uploads/2024.10.17-PSI-Majority-Staff-Report-on-Medicare-Advantage.pdf">investigation</a> by the US Senate permanent subcommittee on investigations found that UnitedHealthcare had ramped up its denials of post-acute care coverage for seniors following strokes, falls and injuries.</p><p>We would like to hear from you about your experience, or the experience of a loved one, of having been denied coverage or access to care at a nursing home facility as a patient with the UnitedHealthcare Medicare advantage plan. We are interested in hearing about the experiences of short- and long-term nursing home residents. You can share your story below.</p> <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/feb/13/nursing-home-patients-insurance">Continue reading...</a>]]></description>
            <link>https://archive.is/2025/https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/feb/13/nursing-home-patients-insurance</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/feb/13/nursing-home-patients-insurance</guid>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[The Guardian]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2025 15:30:41 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NYT's Eric Lipton on How Musk Empire Benefits as He Slashes Fed. Gov't; Trump Cryptocurrency Schemes]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[How is Elon Musk personally benefiting from his role as head of the Department of Government Efficiency? The agency, known as <span class="caps">DOGE</span>, is tasked with slashing &#8220;trillions&#8221; of dollars in federal spending and has set its sights on regulatory agencies, including ones that have opened investigations into Musk&#8217;s business practices. &#8220;At a minimum, it&#8217;s an appearance of conflict of interest,&#8221; says journalist Eric Lipton, who is investigating Musk and <span class="caps">DOGE</span> for <em>The New York Times</em>. Musk&#8217;s business empire is a major beneficiary of government contracts, says Lipton, and &#8220;all of the disruption that is happening across the federal government has benefited his operations.&#8221; Lipton also discusses Trump and his allies&#8217; cryptocurrency schemes and the Trump family&#8217;s investments in the Middle East.]]></description>
            <link>https://archive.is/2025/tag:democracynow.org,2025-02-13:en/story/0eeac3</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">tag:democracynow.org,2025-02-13:en/story/0eeac3</guid>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[Democracy Now]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2025 13:29:11 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Hamas Signals Progress Toward Resumed Hostage Releases]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[The group said that mediators were working “to remove obstacles and close gaps” after the cease-fire deal with Israel hit a roadblock.]]></description>
            <link>https://archive.is/2025/https://www.nytimes.com/2025/02/13/world/middleeast/gaza-israel-ceasefire-hostages.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.nytimes.com/2025/02/13/world/middleeast/gaza-israel-ceasefire-hostages.html</guid>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[New York Times]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2025 13:03:06 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[‘I want more joy, less killing’: Jamaicans say police alone cannot quell gang crime]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Experts, and children in violence-torn areas, see factors such as education and land ownership as keys to progress</p><p>The <a href="http://www.operation-restoration.org/">Operation Restoration Christian</a> school sits amid a line of patched-up housing blocks and streetside cookshops in Trench Town. In an area known as one of Kingston’s inner-city crime hotspots, it was founded as a haven for children caught up in gang violence.</p><p>Inside, boys in smart khaki uniforms and girls in yellow shirts and pleated burgundy skirts sit chatting in groups. The classrooms are adorned with images of Jamaican heroes, such as Marcus Garvey and past prime ministers – a reminder to the children, says the principal, Robert Dixon, of what they might one day accomplish.</p> <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2025/feb/13/jamaica-gang-crime-police">Continue reading...</a>]]></description>
            <link>https://archive.is/2025/https://www.theguardian.com/world/2025/feb/13/jamaica-gang-crime-police</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.theguardian.com/world/2025/feb/13/jamaica-gang-crime-police</guid>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[The Guardian]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2025 11:00:04 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[US wildfire suppressants rife with toxic heavy metals, study finds]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Suppressants a ‘major’ source of toxic pollution that causes heavy-metal levels to spike in the environment</p><p>The US federal government and chemical makers have long concealed the contents of pink wildfire suppressants widely spread by firefighting aircraft to contain blazes, but new test results provide alarming answers – the substances are rife with cadmium, arsenic, chromium and other toxic heavy metals.</p><p>The suppressants are a “major” source of toxic pollution that causes heavy-metal levels to spike in the environment, and the products themselves contain metal levels up to 3,000 times above drinking water limits, the <a href="https://pubs.acs.org/doi/epdf/10.1021/acs.estlett.4c00727?ref=article_openPDF">peer-reviewed research</a> found.</p> <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/feb/13/us-wildfire-suppressants-toxic-study">Continue reading...</a>]]></description>
            <link>https://archive.is/2025/https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/feb/13/us-wildfire-suppressants-toxic-study</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/feb/13/us-wildfire-suppressants-toxic-study</guid>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[The Guardian]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2025 11:00:02 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Liberal Vets Group Gives Spanberger Boost in Virginia Governor’s Race]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[The $500,000 donation to the campaign of Abigail Spanberger, a former representative and C.I.A. officer, is the largest direct contribution in VoteVets’ 20-year history.]]></description>
            <link>https://archive.is/2025/https://www.nytimes.com/2025/02/13/us/politics/spanberger-votevets-virginia-governor.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.nytimes.com/2025/02/13/us/politics/spanberger-votevets-virginia-governor.html</guid>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[New York Times]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2025 10:04:34 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[‘No to ethnic cleansing’: over 350 rabbis sign US ad assailing Trump’s Gaza plan]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Jewish creatives and activists also sign New York Times ad after US president’s proposal to ‘take over Gaza’</p><p>More than 350 rabbis, alongside additional signatories including Jewish creatives and activists, have signed an ad in the New York Times in which they condemn <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2025/feb/05/donald-trump-plan-to-take-over-gaza-strip-netanyahu-visit">Donald Trump’s proposal</a> for the effective ethnic cleansing of Palestinians from Gaza.</p><p>The ad, which was signed by rabbis including Sharon Brous, Roly Matalon and Alissa Wise, as well as Jewish creatives and activists including Tony Kushner, Ilana Glazer, Naomi Klein and Joaquin Phoenix, says: “Trump has called for the removal of all Palestinians from Gaza. Jewish people say no to ethnic cleansing!”</p> <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/feb/13/rabbis-ad-trump-gaza-plan">Continue reading...</a>]]></description>
            <link>https://archive.is/2025/https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/feb/13/rabbis-ad-trump-gaza-plan</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/feb/13/rabbis-ad-trump-gaza-plan</guid>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[The Guardian]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2025 10:00:04 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[ProPublica Updates Supreme Connections Database With Previously Missing Disclosures]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[
                <p class="byline">
                by <a class="name" href="https://www.propublica.org/people/sergio-hernandez">Sergio Hernández</a>                </p>
                                             

                                                                    
            
                <p>ProPublica is a nonprofit newsroom that investigates abuses of power. Sign up to receive <a href="https://www.propublica.org/newsletters/the-big-story?source=54G&amp;placement=top-note&amp;region=national">our biggest stories</a> as soon as they’re published.</p>

            

                

      
  



                    
<p data-pp-blocktype="copy" data-pp-id="1.0">We updated our <a href="https://projects.propublica.org/supreme-connections/">Supreme Connections database</a> with new disclosures on Thursday, adding Justice Samuel Alito’s deferred 2023 filing and eight previously missing disclosures from Justice Clarence Thomas dating back to the 1990s.</p>

<p data-pp-blocktype="copy" data-pp-id="1.1">Supreme Connections is our database that makes it easy for anyone to browse justices’ financial disclosures and to search for connections to people and companies mentioned within them.</p>
        
    
                    
<p data-pp-blocktype="copy" data-pp-id="3.0">This update includes Alito’s 2023 disclosure, which was released in August after he received an extension, as well as eight Thomas filings from the 1990s provided by <a href="http://documented.net/">Documented</a>. Those filings were not previously available in our database. While federal ethics law requires judges to file these disclosures each year, the law requires most filings to be destroyed after six years, making many past disclosures hard to find.</p>

<p data-pp-blocktype="copy" data-pp-id="3.1">Alito’s disclosure includes $900 in concert tickets from Princess Gloria von Thurn und Taxis, which The New York Times reported were <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/10/22/us/politics/samuel-alito-princess-gloria.html">for her annual music festival</a> in Regensburg, Germany. The Bavarian aristocrat <a href="https://www.vanityfair.com/news/2006/06/princesstnt200606">once dubbed the “punk princess”</a> has reinvented herself in recent decades, closely aligning with European conservative and Catholic circles.</p>

<p data-pp-blocktype="copy" data-pp-id="3.2">The newly added Thomas filings, which cover 1992 to 1999, reveal more than 100 gifts or travel-related reimbursements, including more than a dozen private flights, cigars from the late conservative commentator Rush Limbaugh, and a 1997 trip paid for by billionaire Harlan Crow to Bohemian Grove, an all-male retreat in northern California. ProPublica previously reported how <a href="https://www.propublica.org/series/supreme-court-scotus">Crow has provided Thomas with extensive undisclosed luxury travel</a>, including several other trips to Bohemian Grove. Thomas has argued he did not need to disclose such gifts.</p>

<p data-pp-blocktype="copy" data-pp-id="3.3"><a href="https://projects.propublica.org/supreme-connections/">Browse the database</a> to learn more.</p>
        
    
                            
             

                                    
        
                        <p>Do you have any tips on the Supreme Court? Josh Kaplan can be reached by email at <a href="mailto:joshua.kaplan@propublica.org">joshua.kaplan@propublica.org</a> and by Signal or WhatsApp at 734-834-9383. Justin Elliott can be reached by email at <a href="mailto:justin@propublica.org">justin@propublica.org</a> or by Signal or WhatsApp at 774-826-6240.</p>

        

    
                                         ]]></description>
            <link>https://archive.is/2025/https://www.propublica.org/article/propublica-supreme-connections-database-new-filings</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.propublica.org/article/propublica-supreme-connections-database-new-filings</guid>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[ProPublica]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2025 10:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[‘Here lives the monster’s brain’: the man who exposed Switzerland’s dirty secrets]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Inspired by Che Guevara, Jean Ziegler has spent the past 60 years exposing how Switzerland enabled global wrongdoing. His enemies accuse him of treason</p><p>In early 1964, Jean Ziegler, a young Swiss politician, received a phone call from a man claiming to represent Ernesto “Che” Guevara, the Cuban revolutionary and minister of industry. Che would be in Geneva in March for a UN conference on trade policy, and some comrades had suggested Jean might be his chauffeur during his stay. Was Ziegler available for the gig?</p><p>Today, in his tenth decade of life, Ziegler is Switzerland’s most notorious public intellectual. That’s because, over the course of writing about 30 books, serving for close to three decades in the Swiss parliament, and relentlessly crusading for leftwing causes in his free time, Ziegler has made a career of unsparing criticism of his home country and its outsize influence on the rest of the world. In the 1960s, though, he was just another eager young leftist, waiting for his chance to change the world.</p> <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/news/2025/feb/13/here-lives-the-monsters-brain-the-man-who-exposed-switzerlands-dirty-secrets">Continue reading...</a>]]></description>
            <link>https://archive.is/2025/https://www.theguardian.com/news/2025/feb/13/here-lives-the-monsters-brain-the-man-who-exposed-switzerlands-dirty-secrets</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.theguardian.com/news/2025/feb/13/here-lives-the-monsters-brain-the-man-who-exposed-switzerlands-dirty-secrets</guid>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[The Guardian]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2025 05:00:47 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ex-officer convicted in fatal shooting of Black man at New Mexico gas station]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Prosecutors said Brad Lunsford, found guilty of voluntary manslaughter, shot Presley Eze at point-blank range in 2022</p><p>A former police officer was found guilty on Wednesday of voluntary manslaughter in the killing of Presley Eze during a 2022 confrontation at a New Mexico gas station.</p><p>Brad Lunsford, who is white, had pleaded not guilty in the fatal shooting of Eze, who was Black. The former Las Cruces officer’s attorney, Jose Coronado, said he would ask the judge to review the verdict for its legal sufficiency.</p> <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/feb/12/new-mexico-police-shooting-gas-station">Continue reading...</a>]]></description>
            <link>https://archive.is/2025/https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/feb/12/new-mexico-police-shooting-gas-station</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/feb/12/new-mexico-police-shooting-gas-station</guid>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[The Guardian]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2025 02:14:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Czech Dam Project Was Stalled by Bureaucracy. Beavers Built Their Own.]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[The dam project, drafted in 2018 and based on a former military training site south of Prague, had been delayed by land negotiations. Local beavers built several dams, saving the government more than one million euros.]]></description>
            <link>https://archive.is/2025/https://www.nytimes.com/2025/02/12/world/europe/czech-dam-project-was-stalled-by-bureaucracy-beavers-built-their-own.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.nytimes.com/2025/02/12/world/europe/czech-dam-project-was-stalled-by-bureaucracy-beavers-built-their-own.html</guid>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[New York Times]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2025 00:45:31 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Austrian Coalition Talks Collapse, Averting, for Now, a Far-Right Chancellor]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[The plan by the far-right Freedom Party to run Austria was halted by a disagreement over who would lead the all-important Interior Ministry.]]></description>
            <link>https://archive.is/2025/https://www.nytimes.com/2025/02/12/world/europe/austria-coalition-talks-far-right-chancellor.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.nytimes.com/2025/02/12/world/europe/austria-coalition-talks-far-right-chancellor.html</guid>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[New York Times]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2025 00:43:01 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Maria Teresa Horta, the Last of Portugal’s ‘Three Marias,’ Dies at 87]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[The book on which she collaborated with two fellow feminists drew global attention to the repression of women under their country’s dictatorship.]]></description>
            <link>https://archive.is/2025/https://www.nytimes.com/2025/02/11/world/europe/maria-teresa-horta-dead.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.nytimes.com/2025/02/11/world/europe/maria-teresa-horta-dead.html</guid>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[New York Times]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2025 22:16:20 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[California’s Scary Product Warning Labels Might Be Working, Study Says]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[Products must state if they contain chemicals tied to cancer or other risks. As a result, manufacturers have pulled back from using the chemicals, researchers found.]]></description>
            <link>https://archive.is/2025/https://www.nytimes.com/2025/02/12/climate/california-chemical-warning-labels.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.nytimes.com/2025/02/12/climate/california-chemical-warning-labels.html</guid>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[New York Times]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2025 22:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Lawsuit Seeks Access to Migrants Held at Guantanamo Bay]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[Advocacy groups say the Trump administration is denying detainees their legal rights.]]></description>
            <link>https://archive.is/2025/https://www.wsj.com/us-news/law/lawsuit-seeks-access-to-migrants-held-at-guantanamo-bay-2d6ad874</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.wsj.com/us-news/law/lawsuit-seeks-access-to-migrants-held-at-guantanamo-bay-2d6ad874</guid>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[Wall Street Journal]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2025 21:56:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pentagon Official: Hegseth’s Campaign to Scrub DEI History Is a “Dumb” Distraction]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Defense Secretary Pete Hegseth is trying to eliminate all Defense Department DEI efforts. It hasn’t been entirely successful.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://theintercept.com/2025/02/12/pete-hegseth-military-trump-diversity/">Pentagon Official: Hegseth’s Campaign to Scrub DEI History Is a “Dumb” Distraction</a> appeared first on <a href="https://theintercept.com">The Intercept</a>.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://archive.is/2025/https://theintercept.com/2025/02/12/pete-hegseth-military-trump-diversity/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://theintercept.com/2025/02/12/pete-hegseth-military-trump-diversity/</guid>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[The Intercept]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2025 21:18:57 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>