<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[The New Dark Times]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[All the news that's fit to print, minus the sad stuff]]></description>
        <link>https://lovemedicine.github.io/goodnews</link>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2025 15:45:31 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://lovemedicine.github.io/goodnews/notbad.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2025 15:34:31 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>60</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Denver’s public school system sues Trump administration over Ice access to schools]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>School district says expanded immigration enforcement diverts resources and causes decreased attendance</p><p>The <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/denver">Denver</a> public school system (DPS) on Wednesday became the first US school district to sue the <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/trump-administration">Trump administration</a> over its policy of allowing Immigration and Customs Enforcement (Ice) agents in schools.</p><p><a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/colorado">Colorado</a>’s largest public school district argues in the federal lawsuit that the policy has forced schools to divert vital educational resources and caused attendance to plummet.</p> <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/feb/13/denver-trump-ice-lawsuit-schools">Continue reading...</a>]]></description>
            <link>https://archive.is/2025/https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/feb/13/denver-trump-ice-lawsuit-schools</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/feb/13/denver-trump-ice-lawsuit-schools</guid>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[The Guardian]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2025 15:34:31 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[US nursing home patients: have you or your loved one experienced coverage denials from UnitedHealthcare?]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>We would like to hear from people who have been denied access to care as a patient with the UnitedHealthcare Medicare advantage plan</p><p>An October 2024 <a href="https://www.hsgac.senate.gov/wp-content/uploads/2024.10.17-PSI-Majority-Staff-Report-on-Medicare-Advantage.pdf">investigation</a> by the US Senate permanent subcommittee on investigations found that UnitedHealthcare had ramped up its denials of post-acute care coverage for seniors following strokes, falls and injuries.</p><p>We would like to hear from you about your experience, or the experience of a loved one, of having been denied coverage or access to care at a nursing home facility as a patient with the UnitedHealthcare Medicare advantage plan. We are interested in hearing about the experiences of short- and long-term nursing home residents. You can share your story below.</p> <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/feb/13/nursing-home-patients-insurance">Continue reading...</a>]]></description>
            <link>https://archive.is/2025/https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/feb/13/nursing-home-patients-insurance</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/feb/13/nursing-home-patients-insurance</guid>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[The Guardian]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2025 15:30:41 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Champions League review: a fired up Vinícius Júnior and McKennie’s screamer]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>The knockout stages are here, and there were plenty of storylines to digest. We hand out honours and dishonours from the latest round of action</p><p><strong>Feyenoord</strong></p> <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/football/2025/feb/13/champions-league-review-vinicius-junior-weston-mckennie">Continue reading...</a>]]></description>
            <link>https://archive.is/2025/https://www.theguardian.com/football/2025/feb/13/champions-league-review-vinicius-junior-weston-mckennie</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.theguardian.com/football/2025/feb/13/champions-league-review-vinicius-junior-weston-mckennie</guid>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[The Guardian]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2025 15:17:55 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[USL announces intention to start new league at same tier as MLS]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul><li>USL president says new competition is not a threat to MLS</li><li>Would give USL competitions at every level of men’s soccer</li></ul><p>The United Soccer Leagues (USL), the organization that administers most of the lower-division leagues in the United States, will announce on Wednesday that it intends to add a new league to its portfolio: One that is sanctioned as Division I, the same level as MLS.</p><p>The as yet-unnamed league, which USL says it intends to launch in 2027, would give the organization a circuit at each level of the men’s US Soccer system, along with the Division II USL Championship, Division III USL League One, the semi-pro USL League Two, and USL Youth leagues. It will also seemingly open up a direct line of competition between the organization and MLS, years after the two ended their strategic partnership that saw many MLS reserve teams playing in USL leagues.</p> <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/football/2025/feb/13/usl-division-i-league-mls-paul-mcdonough">Continue reading...</a>]]></description>
            <link>https://archive.is/2025/https://www.theguardian.com/football/2025/feb/13/usl-division-i-league-mls-paul-mcdonough</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.theguardian.com/football/2025/feb/13/usl-division-i-league-mls-paul-mcdonough</guid>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[The Guardian]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2025 14:45:39 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Czech Dam Project Was Stalled by Bureaucracy. Beavers Built Their Own.]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[The dam project, drafted in 2018 and based on a former military training site south of Prague, had been delayed by land negotiations. Local beavers built several dams, saving the government more than one million euros.]]></description>
            <link>https://archive.is/2025/https://www.nytimes.com/2025/02/12/world/europe/beavers-prague-czech-republic-dam.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.nytimes.com/2025/02/12/world/europe/beavers-prague-czech-republic-dam.html</guid>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[New York Times]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2025 14:31:39 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[London’s first Roman basilica found under office block]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Archaeologists hail discovery of near-2,000-year-old structure as one of most significant recent finds in the city</p><p>The remains of London’s earliest Roman basilica have been discovered under an office block, in what archaeologists have described as one of the most significant recent discoveries in the capital.</p><p>The almost 2,000-year-old structure was part of the forum, the Roman capital’s social and administrative centre, and built around the late 70s or early 80s AD, just a few decades after the Romans invaded Britain and 20 years after Boudicca sacked and burned the city in AD60.</p> <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2025/feb/13/londons-first-roman-basilica-found-under-office-block">Continue reading...</a>]]></description>
            <link>https://archive.is/2025/https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2025/feb/13/londons-first-roman-basilica-found-under-office-block</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2025/feb/13/londons-first-roman-basilica-found-under-office-block</guid>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[The Guardian]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2025 14:22:21 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[RFK Jr ‘not remotely qualified’ to be health secretary says Schumer before Senate vote – US politics live]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Vaccine sceptic likely to face early vote after wavering Republicans said they would support appointment</p><p><strong>Donald Trump</strong> said he plans to unveil reciprocal tariffs on Thursday but gave no other details, Reuters reports.</p><p>“Today is the big one: reciprocal tariffs,” Trump wrote on his social media platform.</p> <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/live/2025/feb/13/rfk-lutnick-trump-musk-putin-ukraine-us-politics-live-news">Continue reading...</a>]]></description>
            <link>https://archive.is/2025/https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/live/2025/feb/13/rfk-lutnick-trump-musk-putin-ukraine-us-politics-live-news</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/live/2025/feb/13/rfk-lutnick-trump-musk-putin-ukraine-us-politics-live-news</guid>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[The Guardian]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2025 14:15:17 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Live Updates: European Allies Insist That U.S. Talks With Russia Include Ukraine]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[At a NATO meeting in Brussels, defense ministers’ comments appeared to reflect concerns that President Trump and President Vladimir V. Putin of Russia might sideline Ukraine in talks to end the war.]]></description>
            <link>https://archive.is/2025/https://www.nytimes.com/live/2025/02/13/world/russia-ukraine-war-trump</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.nytimes.com/live/2025/02/13/world/russia-ukraine-war-trump</guid>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[New York Times]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2025 14:10:12 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ke Huy Quan: ‘I wish everyone could have their own Oscar moment’]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>The actor on being star-struck by Harrison Ford, colour-blind casting and the question he is asked the most</p><p><strong>Cyndi Lauper</strong><strong>, </strong><strong>Michael Jackson</strong><strong> and </strong><strong>Clint Eastwood</strong><strong> were among the celebrities who dropped by during the filming of </strong><strong>The Goonies</strong><strong>. Who were you most star</strong><strong>-struck by? </strong><em>McScootikins<br></em>Harrison Ford! I was star-struck when Harrison Ford came to visit because I’d made Indy [Indiana Jones and the Temple of Doom]. Spielberg played a big joke on him. There was a biography out of him that he really hated, so Steven went out and bought about 300 copies, so that when Harrison came to visit and walked on to set, the security guard, the gaffers, the camera equipment people, <em>everybody</em> was reading that biography.</p><p><br>
 I remember when we were told that Michael Jackson was going to visit. The cast and crew were so excited. We didn’t know what time he was arriving, so we were constantly looking over our shoulder. Sure enough, when he walked on to the set, everybody just stopped what they were doing – even the guy making the coffee. He was very shy. I think we made him nervous because there were so many people. Then we took those photos that you see on the internet. We were so giddy that he was there. He gave us tickets to watch him perform in Los Angeles, and gave us all a jacket, which some of us still have. Somehow I lost mine, which I’m very mad at myself for.</p> <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/film/2025/feb/13/ke-huy-quan-i-wish-everyone-could-have-their-own-oscar-moment">Continue reading...</a>]]></description>
            <link>https://archive.is/2025/https://www.theguardian.com/film/2025/feb/13/ke-huy-quan-i-wish-everyone-could-have-their-own-oscar-moment</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.theguardian.com/film/2025/feb/13/ke-huy-quan-i-wish-everyone-could-have-their-own-oscar-moment</guid>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[The Guardian]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2025 14:00:03 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Maps: Ukraine’s Borders Pre-2014 Invasion to Now]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[Ukraine’s government wants to restore the country’s frontier to where it was before Russia launched its first invasion more than a decade ago. The U.S. defense secretary said that was “unrealistic.”]]></description>
            <link>https://archive.is/2025/https://www.nytimes.com/2025/02/13/world/europe/ukraine-borders-pre-2014-map-war.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.nytimes.com/2025/02/13/world/europe/ukraine-borders-pre-2014-map-war.html</guid>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[New York Times]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2025 13:54:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Fringe Cause That Could Derail the Republican Agenda]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[Will these strategies do to Trump’s presidency what they did to Biden’s?]]></description>
            <link>https://archive.is/2025/https://www.nytimes.com/2025/02/13/opinion/trump-tax-cuts-club-for-growth.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.nytimes.com/2025/02/13/opinion/trump-tax-cuts-club-for-growth.html</guid>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[New York Times]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2025 13:49:02 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Politicians weigh in on immigration debate after 28 injured as car hits crowd in Munich – Europe live]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Following news suspect is an Afghan man, Olaf Scholz says ‘this is not something we can tolerate or accept’</p><ul><li><a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2025/feb/13/vehicle-driven-into-group-of-people-in-munich">At least 28 injured after car hits group of people in Munich</a></li></ul><p>Poland’s Europe minister <strong>Adam Szłapka</strong> <a href="https://tvn24.pl/polska/rozmowa-trumpa-z-putinem-to-sygnal-ktory-moze-budzic-niepokoj-st8303570">told Polish broadcaster TVN24</a> this morning that he was “concerned” by the message on peace talks sent by Trump, as it followed the logic of “a 19th-century concert of powers: we’ll have a chat and come up with something.”</p><p>“The statement we got from president Trump that they spoke not only about the war, but also other things… it is somewhat strange. [The idea of them] talking about artificial intelligence and so on, while [we are] thinking about the images of the Bucha massacre is somewhat hair-raising.”</p> <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/live/2025/feb/13/ukraine-nato-hegseth-trump-putin-zelenskyy-europe-news-live">Continue reading...</a>]]></description>
            <link>https://archive.is/2025/https://www.theguardian.com/world/live/2025/feb/13/ukraine-nato-hegseth-trump-putin-zelenskyy-europe-news-live</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.theguardian.com/world/live/2025/feb/13/ukraine-nato-hegseth-trump-putin-zelenskyy-europe-news-live</guid>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[The Guardian]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2025 13:46:36 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[US Department of State plans to spend $400m on Tesla armoured vehicles]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Plan raises possibility of more conflicts of interest for Elon Musk as he leads efforts to slash government spending</p><p>The US Department of State is planning to spend $400m buying new Tesla armoured vehicles, even as the carmaker’s boss, Elon Musk, <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/feb/04/musk-regulation-spending">leads efforts to slash government spending</a> under Donald Trump.</p><p>A procurement forecast produced by the department showed the $400m (£320m) proposed spending on “armoured Tesla (production units)”. They are likely to be Cybertrucks, the company’s electric pickup, given Musk’s claims that the vehicle is bulletproof.</p> <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2025/feb/13/us-department-of-state-plans-to-spend-400m-on-tesla-armoured-vehicles-elon-musk">Continue reading...</a>]]></description>
            <link>https://archive.is/2025/https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2025/feb/13/us-department-of-state-plans-to-spend-400m-on-tesla-armoured-vehicles-elon-musk</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2025/feb/13/us-department-of-state-plans-to-spend-400m-on-tesla-armoured-vehicles-elon-musk</guid>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[The Guardian]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2025 13:44:38 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Live briefing: Hamas says it will release Israeli hostages as planned ]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[Hamas said it would carry out the ceasefire agreement “according to the specified timetable,” reversing a vow to delay prisoner releases over alleged Israeli violations.]]></description>
            <link>https://archive.is/2025/https://www.washingtonpost.com/world/2025/02/13/hamas-hostages-gaza-ceasefire/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.washingtonpost.com/world/2025/02/13/hamas-hostages-gaza-ceasefire/</guid>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[Washington Post]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2025 13:44:37 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Man Charged with Killing Roommate, Whose Torso Was Found in a Suitcase.]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[The remains of Edwin Echevarria, 65, were found floating in the East River on Feb. 5. His roommate, Christian Millet, 23, has been charged with second degree murder.]]></description>
            <link>https://archive.is/2025/https://www.nytimes.com/2025/02/13/nyregion/torso-suitcase-east-river.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.nytimes.com/2025/02/13/nyregion/torso-suitcase-east-river.html</guid>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[New York Times]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2025 13:37:40 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Gazans fear return to war amid standoff between Israel and Hamas]]></title>
            <link>https://archive.is/2025/https://www.washingtonpost.com</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.washingtonpost.com</guid>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[Washington Post]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2025 13:30:57 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[A New Generation of ‘Unbeatable’ Fake IDs Is Bedeviling Bouncers]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[Holograms, engravings and just the right polycarbonate make a perfect driver’s license from anywhere you want. The cards are bedeviling bouncers.]]></description>
            <link>https://archive.is/2025/https://www.nytimes.com/2025/02/13/nyregion/students-high-tech-fake-ids.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.nytimes.com/2025/02/13/nyregion/students-high-tech-fake-ids.html</guid>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[New York Times]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2025 13:23:02 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Toast, Trees and a Wassailing Queen: An Ancient English Ritual Is Back]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[The centuries-old tradition of wassailing is making a comeback in rural England, with rituals and revelry meant to chase away evil spirits and the winter blues.]]></description>
            <link>https://archive.is/2025/https://www.nytimes.com/2025/02/13/world/europe/england-wassailing-cider-tradition.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.nytimes.com/2025/02/13/world/europe/england-wassailing-cider-tradition.html</guid>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[New York Times]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2025 13:18:55 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Southern California Braces for Storm Damage in Wildfire Areas]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[An intense storm could cause flooding and debris flows in areas burned by wildfires. Some residents have begun to evacuate.]]></description>
            <link>https://archive.is/2025/https://www.nytimes.com/2025/02/13/weather/california-storm-flooding.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.nytimes.com/2025/02/13/weather/california-storm-flooding.html</guid>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[New York Times]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2025 13:17:35 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Hamas Signals Progress Toward Resumed Hostage Releases]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[The group said that mediators were working “to remove obstacles and close gaps” after the cease-fire deal with Israel hit a roadblock.]]></description>
            <link>https://archive.is/2025/https://www.nytimes.com/2025/02/13/world/middleeast/gaza-israel-ceasefire-hostages.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.nytimes.com/2025/02/13/world/middleeast/gaza-israel-ceasefire-hostages.html</guid>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[New York Times]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2025 13:03:06 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>